Inhyeok Choi

CV updated Jul. 2024

Department of Mathematics, Cornell University 310 Malott Hall, Ithaca, NY 14853, USA

Email: inhyeokchoi48@gmail.com

Website: https://inhyeokchoi48.github.io

Research Interests

My research lies in the intersection of geometric topology, geometric group theory and probability theory. Research keywords include Teichmüller space, mapping class groups, Outer space, $Out(F_N)$, Gromov hyperbolic spaces, CAT(0) spaces, random walks, and dynamics of groups acting on spaces.

Positions

07/2024-	Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, United States
	Harry Kesten Assistant Professor (Post-doc)
03/2023 – 06/2024	Korea Institute for Advanced Study, Seoul, South Korea
	Project research fellow (-07/2023), June E Huh Fellow (08/2023-) (Post-doc)
	Mentor: Prof. Sang-hyun Kim
03/2024 – 06/2024	Fields Institute, Toronto, ON, Canada
	Marsden Postdoctoral Fellowship (visiting for the program "Thematic program on
	Randomness and Geometry")
	Mentor: Prof. Giulio Tiozzo

Education

09/2018-02/2023	Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Daejeon, South Korea M.S. & Ph.D. Integrated Program in Mathematical Sciences
	Advisor: Prof. Hyungryul Baik
03/2015 - 08/2018	Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Daejeon, South Korea
	B.Sc. in Physics, Mathematical Sciences, and Biological Sciences
	Summa Cum Laude

Other Educational Experiences

12/2018 - 02/2019	Exchange student, Tokyo Institute of Technology
08/2017 - 02/2018	Exchange student, École Polytechnique Féderale de Lausanne
12/2015 - 06/2017	Undergraduate researcher, Biomedical Optics Lab, KAIST
	Advisor: Prof. YongKeun Park
06/2015 – 08/2015	Exchange student, University of California, Berkeley

Awards and Honors

02/2023	Best Thesis Award, 2023, Dept. of Mathematical Sciences, KAIST
08/2022	Best TA Award, 2022 Spring semester, Dept. of Mathematical Sciences, KAIST
03/2017	Dean's list, 2016 Fall semester, College of Natural Sciences, KAIST
12/2016	Silver Prize, Korean Undergraduate Mathematics Competition (전국
	대학생수학경시대회), Korean Mathematical Society
03/2015 – 08/2018	Korea Presidential Science Scholarship (대통령과학장학생), Korea Student Aid
	Foundation
03/2015 – 08/2018	KAIST Presidential Fellowship

Publications & Preprints

- 1. Confined subgroups in groups with contracting elements With *Ilya Gekhtman, Wenyuan Yang and Tianyi Zheng.* Preprint (2024). arXiv:2405.09070.
- 2. Contracting isometries and differentiability of the escape rate Preprint (2024). arXiv:2403.09992.
- 3. Random walks on groups and superlinear divergent geodesics With *Kunal Chawla*, *Vivian He and Kasra Rafi*. Preprint (2023). arXiv:2310.18506.
- 4. Genericity of contracting geodesics in groups With *Kunal Chawla and Giulio Tiozzo*. Preprint (2023). arXiv:2308.01877.
- 5. Random walks and contracting elements III: Outer space and outer automorphism group Preprint (2023). arXiv:2212.12122.
- 6. Random walks and contracting elements II: Translation lengths and quasi-isometric embedding Preprint (2023). arXiv:2212.12119.
- 7. Random walks and contracting elements I: Deviation inequality and limit laws Preprint (2023). arXiv:2207.06597.
- 8. Random walks on mapping class groups (survey paper) With *Hyungryul Baik*.

EMS Surveys in Mathematical Sciences, 9 (2022), no. 2, pp. 279–320. https://doi.org/10.4171/EMSS/59.

- 9. Pseudo-Anosovs are exponentially generic in mapping class groups Preprint (2021). To appear in **Geometry & Topology**. arXiv:2110.06678.
- 10. Central limit theorem and geodesic tracking on hyperbolic spaces and Teichmüller spaces Advances in Mathematics, Volume 431, 109236 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aim.2023.109236.
- 11. Linear growth of translation lengths of random isometries on Gromov hyperbolic spaces and Teichmüller spaces

With Hyungryul Baik and Dongryul M. Kim.

Preprint (2021). To appear in Journal of the Institute of Mathematics of Jussieu. arXiv:2103.13616.

- 12. Simple length spectra as moduli for hyperbolic surfaces and rigidity of length identities With *Hyungryul Baik and Dongryul M. Kim.*Preprint (2020). arXiv:2012.05652.
- On the surjectivity of the Symplectic representation of the mapping class group With Hyungryul Baik and Dongryul M. Kim.
 Topology and its Applications, Volume 322, 108334 (2022). doi.org/10.1016/j.topol.2022.108334.
- 14. Topological entropy of pseudo-Anosov maps from a typical Thurston construction With Hyungryul Baik and Dongryul M. Kim.

International Mathematics Research Notices, Volume 2022, No. 24, pp. 19762-19904. (2022) https://doi.org/10.1093/imrn/rnab167

15. Inhyeok Choi, KyeoReh Lee, and YongKeun Park. Compensation of aberration and speckle noise in quantitative phase imaging using lateral shifting and spiral phase integration. **Optics Express**, 25(24) pp. 30771-30779 (2017).

Invited Talks

- 2023.07.29. TBA. Geometry in Groups 2024. ICTS, Bangalore, India.
- 2024.05.13. Continuity of escape rate of random walks on CAT(0) spaces. Dynamics of group actions and random walks on groups, Fields Institute.
- 2024.05.03. Hyperbolicity of geodesics, counting and random walks. (series of 4 talks) Riverside Workshop on Geometric Group Theory 2024, UC Riverside. (Tentative)
- 2024.04.08. Genericity of pseudo-Anosov mapping classes. Young Geometric Group Theory XII, Bristol, UK. (Tentative)
- 2024.04.04. Genericity of pseudo-Anosovs (and fully irreducibles). *Princeton Topology Seminar, Princeton University*.
- 2024.04.02. Genericity of pseudo-Anosov mapping classes. $Brandeis\ Topology\ Seminar,\ Brandeis\ University.$
- 2024.03.20. Random walks, superlinear divergence and quasi-isometry. *UBC Probability Seminar, University of British Columbia*.
- 2024.03.15. Growth of normal subgroups of a hyperbolic group. GT GAPS Seminar. (Online)
- 2024.02.29. Normal subgroups, confined subgroups and growth. Korea-France Workshop on Dynamical Group Theory, KIAS.
- 2024.01.17. Regularity of the escape rate and the asymptotic entropy of a random walk. KAIST GT Fair 2024, Busan, Korea.
- 2023.11.03. Genericity of contracting elements in groups. SNU Rookies Workshop 2023, Yangpeong, Korea.
- 2023.10.28. Generic mapping classes are pseudo-Anosov. 2023 KMS Fall Meeting, SNU.
- 2023.10.05. Genericity of contracting elements in groups. Tokyo-Seoul Conference in Mathematics 2023, The University of Tokyo.
- 2023.09.11. Random walks on groups without an action on hyperbolic spaces. Topology seminar, KAIST.
- 2023.09.04. Genericity of contracting elements in groups. World of Group Craft III. (Online)
- 2023.08.21. Genericity of contracting elements in groups. The 4th Korea-France Conference in Mathematics, KIAS.
- 2023.07.14. Geometry and dynamics of a finitely generated group. Workshop on Quantum Analysis 2023, Sokcho, Korea.
- 2023.04.20. Random walks on non-positively curved spaces: rate of escape, CLT and large deviation principle. *Conference on Probability and PDE, KAIST.*
- 2023.04.06. Counting pseudo-Anosov mapping classes. (series of 4 talks) $\it Virtual \ Seminar \ on \ Geometry \ and \ Topology, \it KIAS.$
- 2023.02.09. Asymmetry of a generic outer automorphism of a free group. The 18th East Asian Conference on Geometric Topology. (Online)
- 2022.11.08. Random subgroup is quasi-isometrically embedded. Geometry and Topology Seminar, CUNY.
- 2022.11.08. The log-regularity of the hitting measure on the Gromov boundary. *Group actions, Geometry and Dynamics Seminar, Yale University.*
- 2022.11.02. Asymmetry of a typical outer automorphism. $Geometry\ and\ Topology\ Seminar,$ $Temple\ university.$
- 2022.10.27. Simple length spectrum of a hyperbolic surface. Hyperbolic lunch, University of Toronto.
- 2022.10.24. Mapping class group, Teichmüller space and Bers' proof of Nielsen-Thurston's classification. *Dynamics Seminar, University of Toronto*.
- 2022.05.12. Typical behavior of random mapping classes and outer automorphisms. Fudan Topology Seminar. (Online)

- 2022.04.11. Limit laws beyond hyperbolic spaces. AIM Workshop "Random walks beyond hyperbolic groups", San Jose, CA United States
- 2021.12.03. Limit laws for random walks on mapping class groups. Conformal Dynamics and Groups Seminar, BICMR. (Online)
- 2021.11.29. Random walks on mapping class groups favor pseudo-Anosovs. *Dynamics Seminar*, *University of Toronto*. (Online)
- 2021.11.18. Random walks, counting problems and genericity of loxodromics. *Geometry and Topology Seminar, Technion*. (Online)
- 2021.10.06. Random walks on Gromov hyperbolic spaces and Teichmüller spaces. *Tokyo Tech Topology Seminar*. (Online)
- 2021.07.22. Random walks on Gromov hyperbolic spaces and Teichmüller spaces. Pacific $Dynamics\ Seminar.$ (Online)
- 2021.02.03. Simple length spectra of a generic hyperbolic surface determine its isometry class. Virtual Seminar on Geometry and Topology. (Online)

Contributed Talks

- 2022.05.31. Frequently contracting geodesics and random mapping class. *PK2 Topology Workshop*.
- 2022.04.25. Limit laws and their consequences on MCG and Out(Fn). 5-min lightning talk, *IHP*Conference "Mapping Class Groups and Out(Fn)".
- 2022.01.18. Random mapping classes are pseudo-Anosov. The 17th East Asian Conference on Geometric Topology. (Online)
- 2021.01.26. Rigidity of length Identities of hyperbolic surfaces. The 16th East Asian Conference on Geometric Topology. (Online)
- 2020.10.30. Random walks and mapping class groups. 10-minute talk at *Geometric Group Theory in East Asia*. (Online)

Conference organization

- 2023.12.18–20. Hyperbolic Geometry of Numbers, KIAS (with Prof. Sang-hyun Kim, Prof. Ser-Peow Tan)
- 2023.09.27–28. The 1st Korea-Chile Workshop on Dynamical Group Theory, Incheon, Korea. (with Prof. Sang-hyun Kim)

Teaching

- 2022F TA, MAS102 Calculus II & MAS430 Combinatorial Topology
- 2022S TA, MAS109 Linear algebra and Applications & MAS201 DE and Applications
- 2021F TA, MAS201 DE and Applications & MAS441 Lebesgue Integration Theory
- 2021S TA, MAS109 Linear algebra and Applications & MAS331 Topology
- 2020F TA, MAS102 Calculus II & MAS441 Lebesgue Integration Theory
- 2020S Head TA, MAS201 DE and Applications
- 2019F TA, MAS201 DE and Applications & MAS441 Lebesgue Integration Theory
- 2019S TA, MAS201 DE and Applications & MAS331 Topology
- 2018F TA, MAS355 Mathematical Statistics
- 2017S, 2018S Undergraduate TA, MAS101 Calculus I

Service & Outreach

• Refereed for Annales Henri Lebesgue, Mathematical Reviews.

 \bullet Published a series of math cartoons on KIAS webzine $\langle {\rm Horizon} \rangle$ (in Korean)

References

Prof. Hyungryul Baik, KAIST hrbaik@kaist.ac.kr

Prof. Ilya Gekhtman, Technion ilyagekh@gmail.com

Prof. Sébastien Gouëzel, Université de Rennes 1 sebastien.gouezel@univ-rennes1.fr

Prof. Kasra Rafi, University of Toronto rafi@math.toronto.edu

Prof. Giulio Tiozzo, University of Toronto tiozzo@math.utoronto.ca

(Teaching) Prof. Moon-Jin Kang, KAIST moonjinkang@kaist.ac.kr